Today, we will learn about epilepsy, a common neurological condition that affects millions of people worldwide.
What is epilepsy?
It is a neurological disorder that causes seizures, episodes characterized by abnormal electrical activity in the brain.
There are various types of seizures.
Generalized seizures affect both hemispheres of the brain, while focal seizures affect only one part.
The causes of epilepsy are varied: they may include genetics, trauma, brain infections, or strokes.
To diagnose epilepsy, studies such as an electroencephalogram are performed.
Treatments include antiepileptic medications, and in some cases, surgery.
With appropriate treatment, many people with epilepsy can lead full and active lives.
If you have epilepsy or know someone who does, remember that support and understanding are essential.